[Music]
hi guys
my name is samrith and today we're in
manulife towering health cocktail into
one of the few minority agents
who'll be working here in the insurance
industry so come and see what we're
going to talk about today
let's not waste any more time let's talk
to hack to the main man we're going to
intro today
how are you hector great man how are you
feeling i'm great
you're great yeah so you know like we're
here in manual life tower
in no time now and you know hector is a
man you know he'll be working man life
for a year and a half
and you know he's making a minority team
you know because
in hong kong and not a lot of minority
is that you're taking an insurance
industry not a lot of them
so first of all you know we can get rid
of that later but
tell me more about yourself hi my name
is hector i've been working in the
insurance industry for over a year now
and to be honest with you it's been fun
you manage your own clients
you build your own team it's quite fast
to get into leadership if you wanted to
it's going to be a lot of hard work but
it's worth it because it's like school
as well
there's a lot to learn and learning does
not stop so
if you're interested in consistent
growth and
like what they say a little bit of
uncomfortable is good
and pressure because that means you're
growing as long as it's good pressure
then that's great and this industry
honestly there's a lot to learn so if
you love learning
this place is like school i'm not sure
how it is with other firms but here we
learn every day
if you talk about like rap because i
know there's a song you've been you
published a few songs
and you got a new song coming up as well
so you know rap
and manny life what made you and pursue
a career in insurance
i don't like the music industry if you
go through it
in the mainstream section you have to
rap about
you know what i'm talking about it's
just the same old recycled topic over
and over
it's all about women drugs alcohol and
to get deeper
to that there's pretty much nothing good
you're putting out there to educate
people that watch you and the ones you
affect are the youth
usually they're below 20 right they're
the biggest fans of hip hop
and of course for ogs way back in the
90s those people are
probably like 40 50s right now but
hip-hop has changed so much from what it
was to what it is today
and it's not that i'm romanticizing
about what is
happening in the past compared to now
but
if i want to make money there i have to
adapt and this is one thing i didn't
want to do because
the reality of performing in clubs is
people showing up yes they like their
songs
but they're all getting drunk and
not really something i liked honestly
when i experienced it what do you think
is constraining hong kong
because i know like a lot of people try
to you'll get to the scene and
everything but what is
stopping us in hong kong especially the
problem with hong kong is
i'm the best i'm the best i'm making
money i'm making money but the truth is
money is tough here
the problem is separation right um
there are cities i forgot which one
already
but that's where ti came from i think
they supported each other where they are
or let's say detroit eminem and the rest
or slaughterhouse all of them
work together and when you work together
you get a lot of views
a lot of fans a lot of following which
means business
problem with hong kong is we started
straight out of hong kong me and mohit
right right
so we gathered all the artists together
some didn't want to perform yet
until they saw results right now
artists are going to come to the show
and they're going to ask for a budget oh
can you pay me 2 000 and we're like okay
can you at least
guarantee us 10 people it's like nah man
i don't know about the people you worry
about that
right so it's like if you're gonna ask
for
ten thousand you better be able to bring
30 000 in the table
right so i think it's very immature on
the business side
it's very immature on collaborating
together because if
they work together as one hong kong
never even
succeeded making a mixtape or an album
as one like everyone in the hip-hop
scene
if they're able to do that then they put
hong kong hip-hop
in the map but no it's the mentality of
i'm the best
so i'm gonna get what i can get and i'll
keep you below if i can keep you though
so ego comes in basically
like many life you will be here for like
a while right
why many life well one point is
i dated someone who was working here all
right and i was like
[Music]
i'm not into insurance at that time as
well because
you know one of those hard sellers i buy
a product and i don't know what the heck
i bought
then i cut it right so bad impression
usually
comes to my market for filipinos not
much trust this
and non-local so i can't speak for them
but i do know there's not much
tapping into that market as well and
getting to
why this brand that's one reason my
girlfriend's here i better work together
with someone i'm with right so we can
build the
vision together right and secondly is
brand equity
uh manulife in terms of market share for
mpf
it's above 24 now is what i know right
and
that's a lot in in terms of the whole
market it's like a backup thing right
insurance something like oh you never
know what would happen yeah
but just buy it because for the sake of
it you know what if it happened
what if never happened so how do you
convince
people to get insurance it's very simple
it's like
you study for over 20 years to build
yourself
to a certain extent to be able to earn
an income
that you want like let's say you want to
be a lawyer you want to be earning 100
000 200 000 or more a month
okay you're earning that amount and then
you start investing in properties
right and you start investing in other
things
so anything in life you're ready for
right
but health no right
can happen anytime my friend 2009 heart
disease no insurance she had to queue up
in the public hospital for nine years
eight to nine years and then she had an
operation but doesn't mean she can buy
insurance at that point right
so what i'm trying to say here is we all
work hard we build ourselves as a
business first
to build other things so when we buy a
car
when you buy a car where you insure it
when you buy a property will you insure
it
right and when let's say we start a
business and we have 20 staff
we have to buy employees compensation
insurance for our staff
right but if we're not insured
we're the reason why all of this exists
so
the the best thing i always ask them is
if there is a
goose and it lays golden eggs and you
make
money with those eggs when you sell it
in the market what are you gonna insure
the eggs
or the goose nice
that makes sense right right goose is
you right so it's just
risk management honestly and if you
want to be protected in every single way
possible
you have to protect your money you don't
protect your money by keeping it all in
the bank
you have to invest in yourself
everyone's investing in other things but
they don't invest in themselves
right which is their health health
starts first then you can make money
you can invest all the money in the
world in your businesses and you can
make millions of dollars
but if it's the worst sickness in the
world you can still lose all of that
millions or you've got to sell assets in
order to get that
money you need to treat yourself right
so that's why insurance first even if
it's a basic coverage
so do you think like in hong kong do you
think the minorities are actually
equipped
with like the good knowledge of
financial literacy
no no not at all if you look at the
whole world the educational system they
don't talk about financial literacy at
all that's right that's one point
second in hong kong i have local friends
they say seven out of ten mom and dad
will always tell them
means buy insurance right or uh west
right or my law buy property right this
is a habit
so every time when these graduates
graduate okay i gotta look for my agent
i gotta look for my real estate agent
maybe i invest in real estate in another
country that's already in their mind
it's programmed that way
but for ethnic minorities it's always um
let's apply for government housing four
of us are working in the family they
said if we
want to apply for the housing few of us
should quit because we don't pass the
eligibility
right so honestly there's many ways
to play in this i see this whole world
as a game
right this is all man-made we're stuck
in it
and we got to play in it and it's either
you're in the winning side
where you're earning or you're in the
losing side where you're getting creamed
so what do you think like you know money
is important financial literacy is very
important for us
to you know for the future to build to
make money and everything right
so why do you think not a lot of
minorities taking up the jobs or like
working
in this industry what do you think is
like stopping them and why what do you
think about it
still the school system the school
system i hated school
like i don't know why the heck i was in
school honestly from from kindergarten
was all right but primary
i started to question it then high
school i have to choose these courses
and i'm not interested at all
i hate math right i hate algebra but i
have to
do math where i am now so i actually
studied so
in the end when when i finally graduated
i realized okay i need to study this so
i studied multimedia that was for music
photography videography
then i started to like business then i
did a business
diploma then that's when i had to do
accounting and i'm like you know what
it's worth it so i started to like
studying more i joined this industry i
have to study five papers i pass four
i'm able to pass so the thing is i think
the problem in schools is they do not
tap
into what the student wants if the
student wants to be a
cop or they want to be a fireman
they want to be a lawyer they want to be
a
accountant they should ask them up front
the moment they're
very young maybe four or five six years
old and then tell them okay you want to
be a fireman you need to know fluent
cantonese in order to end
the industry so you need to manage your
cantonese and make sure it's fluent
and then in order to be more competitive
you need to add mandarin
then the kids will know but i didn't
have that guidance
all i know is if i go to school if i get
a's
i'm good if i'm in the lower class and i
get c
or fail then i won't succeed in life
that's another problem a lot of teachers
say if you don't do
good in your grades you fail in life
that's why a lot of people
that were i was always in the c class so
it's okay but then anything beyond c
teachers will always say might as well
just fail no need to take your
ces it was hkces at the time so it was a
big problem so all the students
are just you know what's cool school
teachers don't care about us i'm not
saying all
there are teachers that care but a huge
majority is just
i think it's a broken system right right
and within that broken system if the
parents are not smart
like what happened to me was i had a
teacher in primary was like
i'll teach you math i'll teach you all
the formulas only once if you can't
understand i won't teach you again
so i come back home mom dad what is this
right and they didn't come from uni
either
sorry i don't know so that's when i lost
heart for school that's like
screw it but now i want to because
where i am i can study and i have to
study
i have to keep getting better so
in school you're taught to not make
mistakes
right but the most successful people in
life make mistakes
definitely a lot of mistakes and then
you learn from the mistakes then you
improve it
just like the one who made the light
bulb so what do you think is the easiest
way for you you know like
financial literacy finance we need to
know about finance
we can't change the system as you can
see we can never change it we can but
not anytime soon so what do you think is
the best way you know like slowly slowly
let people know
about it no no no only minorities man
just about people
how can we actually improve the
financial literacy financial knowledge
because
again to change the system it's not
possible we are like what peanuts
right how can we change it what do you
think in your perspective
that's why i joined actually um it's a
big problem
in filipinos right for example a lot
retire broke
and kids have to take up everything they
have to be the ones working taking care
of the bills
so instantly we have babies the moment
we
start working right when parents retire
there are babies right so i've seen
situations where
they didn't get married because they're
just taking care of everything
right and i heard it also happens in
indian families
not to offend anybody just being fully
open and
for nepalese i heard they also
have habits that have been around for a
couple of years and
it's cycling to a point where there's
just no one
impacting their lives right now
the filipino advisors that are baby
boomers in manual have already left so
i'm the only one filipino at the moment
right okay and i have competitors in
other firms but thing is like our
industry
is very lucrative we can earn a lot but
if you do your job well you can earn
way more but do it with heart like my
girlfriend
she had 60 clients she had over 40 plus
recommendations in one year in 2018
right so do well you get recommendations
do a one-off sale just for the sake of
selling you just get that one sale
and they might cut the plan because they
don't know what they bought so
in order to make an impact we need to
have people in the industry that
actually care
because it's very sensitive to a point
where if i join
and i just sign clients for the sake of
signing
i'm gonna create a ripple effect of
insurance is bad
and that's been the problem way back
even probably before i was born right
that's
everything i hear and it's the same
thing for the nepali community because i
have a
nepalese guy on my team i have an engine
in my team
indians they're more open to be honest
nepalese they love to save
and most of them go into the banks and
then they get sold plans that they don't
know
why they bought it right so in the banks
it's a different story they
they just sell there's no long-term
relationship
so when you get a deal you get a deal
for us
what you're paying for is long term and
in order for us to last long term we
have to support you as much as you
support us
if we get a lot of recommendations from
our clients
that makes us last longer in the
industry and if we build our team
then longer in the industry so the only
way to make an impact
people only believe when they see the
result right right so from one year
uh i'm unit manager if i get to a
director level then people will respect
my advice more because like if you think
about like you're actually building a
minority team yeah what do you think the
biggest challenge in hong kong
to build that minority team in mandarin
light especially
well in recruitment the process is very
simple you look for people with charisma
right energy and what is their main
points that
drive them every morning and i don't
just recruit people
right you have to look for people who
can see the vision what is the
actual target and if they can align that
uh
eye to eye with you then it's easier to
work with them
so the two people i'm with right now
they're pretty much aligned to what we
need to achieve
and what we need to achieve is go fast
and
create an impact in the market to a
point where instead of just us
approaching them to tell them they must
learn this
they approach us and when they approach
us then they're more open to learn you
can say pretty much anything you want
and the main goal is make their nose
bleed
right because that's exactly my reaction
when i learned about investments even
way before
manual life that's why i asked here as
well so
there's a lot to learn and just that a
lot of people are close to it
thank you man that was a really good
interview man a good answer good
questions
love it man i wish you all the best get
more people on this team and you know
make the name great you know make it
bigger and bigger and thank you guys as
hector for you
a great man big future big potential
and stay tuned
[Music]